A Guide to the Warner W. White papers, 1803-1892
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Warner W. White papers, 1803-1892
The Library of Virginia
53126, 53133
.225 cubic feet (1 box)
Warner W. White
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Warner W. White was born 3 August 1798 in Hanover County, Virginia, to William White (1751-1812) and Catherine White (b. 1762). White served in Captain Hickman's Company, Virginia militia, during the War of 1812. White was a farmer in Hanover County and held several enslaved persons. He married Harriet Anderson (b. ca. 1815) of Caroline County, Virginia, and they had two children.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1803-1892, of Warner W. White (b. 1798) of Hanover County, Virginia, consisting of accounts, certificates, deeds, forms, judicial records, letters, promissory notes, receipts, tax records, and other documents regarding White's purchase and hire of enslaved persons, and his purchase of groceries and dry-goods. It also covers his and his family's efforts to secure property in Randolph County, (West) Virginia; as well as Harriet White's (b. ca. 1815) efforts to receive a pension for White's military service during the War of 1812. Papers also include family correspondence from brothers living in Roanoke County, Virginia, and Owensboro, Kentucky.
Contents List
- Papers, 1803-1804, 1816 (Folder 1)
- Papers, 1823-1828 (Folder 2)
- Papers, 1831-1832 (Folder 3)
- Papers, 1833 (Folder 4)
- Papers, 1834-1839 (Folder 5)
- Papers, 1841-1845 (Folder 6)
- Papers, 1846-1850 (Folder 7)
- Papers, 1851-1854 (Folder 8)
- Papers, 1855-1856 (Folder 9)
- Papers, 1857 (Folder 10)
- Papers, 1858-1860 (Folder 11)
- Papers, 1861-1868 (Folder 12)
- Papers, 1870-1880 (Folder 13)
- Papers, 1881-1892 (Folder 14)
- Papers, undated (Folder 15)